Guide to the William Blackburn Papers, 1859-1985 RL.00115
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 3 boxes
  - Photographs and postcards of students, family, travels (Box 38)
- Restricted Series, 1 box
  These materials are restricted.
  - Blackburn's grade books, 1927-1969 and n.d. (Box 39)
  - Academic records: Blackburn family grades and grade reports, 1920-1955 (Box 39)
- Volumes, 2 boxes
  These volumes were from Blackburn's personal library and include his annotations and notes.
  - The Golden Hind, ed. by Lumson and Smith. 1942. (Box 40)
  - Shakespeare: Five Plays, ed. by Kittredge. 1941. (Box 40)
  - Understanding Fiction, ed. by Brooks and Warren. 1959. (Box 40)
  - Seventeenth Century Prose and Poetry, 1st edition, ed. by Coggin and Witherspoon. (Box 41)
  - Seventeenth Century Prose and Poetry, 2nd edition, ed. by Witherspoon and Warnke. (Box 41)
- Accession (2007-0129), 1937-1972, 6 folders
  - Mary April Blackburn Hill correspondence (incoming), 1945-1972 (Box 42)
  - Mary April Blackburn Hill correspondence, 1937-1972 (5 folders) (Box 42)
- Accession (2008-0071), 1 folder
  - Elizabeth Blackburn letters to Clark and Virginia Blackburn (Box 42)
- Accession (2010-0013), 1 box
  Includes correspondence between William and Elizabeth Blackburn written during the breakup of their marriage. Also included are articles, clippings, genealogical materials, a speech, interviews, and miscellaneous printed materials from students and colleagues.
  - Notes relating to William Blackburn from Alexander Blackburn's Meeting the Professor (Box 43)
  - Letters of William Blackburn and Elizabeth Blackburn, as well as some letters from Alexander Blackburn, Mary April Blackburn, Clark Blackburn, lawyers, et al. (Box 43)
  - Clippings (Box 43)
  - Family history materials, including genealogy (Box 43)
  - Articles and a speech (Box 43)
  - Printed materials from about about students and colleagues (Box 43)
- Accession (2014-0213), 4 boxes.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains the correspondence of the Blackburn family from the 1920s-1980s.
  - Correspondence
    Arranged chronologically whenever possible.
    - Amy Blackburn Correspondence, 1920-1968, undated; 11 folders (Box 46, Box 45)
      Mostly letters from Amy Blackburn written to George and Libby Blackburn, the brother and sister-in-law of William Blackburn.
    - William Blackburn Correspondence
      Correspondence from William Blackburn to his brother George Blackburn, his sister Mallie Robertson, his nephew Brooke Blackburn, and his mother Amy Blackburn, as well as a few miscellaneous letters and fragments.
      - William Blackburn to George Blackburn, 1920s-1972; 6 folders (Box 46, Box 47)
      - William Blackburn to Mallie Blackburn Robertson, 1920s-1960s (Box 47)
      - William Blackburn to Brooke Blackburn, 1948-1970 (Box 47)
      - William Blackburn to Amy Blackburn, 1922-1960s (Box 47)
      - William Blackburn: Miscellaneous Family Correspondence, 1945-1967 (Box 47)
      - Fragments, undated (Box 47)
    - Charles Blackburn Correspondence, 1920-1943 (Box 48)
      Letters from Charles Blackburn, the father of William Blackburn.
    - Mallie Blackburn Robertson Correspondence, 1921-1980; 3 folders (Box 48)
      Letters from Malvina (Mallie) Blackburn Robertson to her brother, George Blackburn, and her mother, Amy Blackburn.
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 48)
- Oversize Material
  - Clipping (Oversize-folder 1)